（ディソナス）ハハハハハハ！
This is…the Saezuri…
that has slumbered here
for many years.
コイツが　ここに
長年　眠っていた　さえずり。
It is a legacy from ages past!
古代の遺産だ。
I wasn't expecting such resistance
from the guards,
思いのほか
防人どもの抵抗が厳しくて→
so obtaining it wasn't easy…
手に入れるのに苦労したがな。
（ドック）じゃあ…。
Then…
The village head should've
minded his own business.
村長め　余計なことをしよって。
I wasted precious time
in gathering the "sounds."
音を揃えるのに
ムダな時間を食っちまった。
Then the one
who attacked the village…
じゃあ　村を襲ったのは…。
That was me.
俺だ。　俺が　コイツにやらせた。
I put him up to it.
キサマ！
Why you—!
俺が　失った力を取り戻すために→
Do you know what
I went through
どんだけ苦労したことか。
in order to regain
the power I lost…?
ここの伝承にたどり着いて
町長にまでなって→
After learning about the legend,
I went as far as
隠された秘密を　ほじくり出して→
becoming the head of
the village to dig around…
そして　確信を得たんだ。
and uncover the hidden secret.
さあ　どこだ？　残りの音は。
So, where are
the remaining "sounds"?
いたぶってる時間も惜しいんだ。
I don't have time to waste.
言えば　楽に死なせてやるぞ。
If you tell me,
I will let you die painlessly.
いや　もう殺して
穢土転生で　しゃべらせるか。
Or maybe,
I should kill you and
ハハハハハハハハッ！
make you talk with
the Reanimation.
（ナルト）テメエ！
いやぁ…　ナルト君。
Why you—!
And you, Naruto.
You're amazing!
すごいな　キミは。
あの暁のペインを
倒したそうじゃないか。
I hear you brought down Pain
of the Akatsuki.
この私でさえ
敗れたというのに。
Even someone like me
couldn't beat him.
そのせいで　力を失ったが
それでも…。
That's how I lost my power.
テメエの過去なんざ　どうでもいい！
– But I lived…
– I could care less about your past!
おっちゃんに手を出したら→
If you lay a hand on him,
I'll kill you!
ぶっ殺すぞ！
ぐわっ！
Those snakes…consume chakra…
（カブト）その蛇たちは　チャクラを食らう。
The more you increase your chakra,
the tighter they squeeze.
キミが　チャクラを高めれば高めるほど→
拘束が強くなるのさ。
You bastard!
You're so full of yourself.
クソが　偉そうに！
Just who do you think you are?
何様のつもりだ！
（ソラ）キャッ！
（レオ）こ　これ…。
H-Here!
This is what you want, right?
これだろ？
お前らの欲しがってるやつ。
You can have it,
so let Dokku Sensei and Naruto go!
やるから
ドック先生とナルト兄ちゃんを返せ！
どうやら　音は
子供たちが持っていたようだね。
It seems these kids
had the "sounds."
なに？
What?!
上に来ている。
They're up above.
健気に　アンタを
助けに来たみたいだ。
It seems they're so brave,
they've come to save you.
（ネジ）カブト…　おそらく分身と→
Kabuto…
He's likely a clone…
and about five children.
たぶん　子供が５人。
（シセル）あの子たち！
家にいないと思ったら　なんで？
The kids! I wondered
where they went… Why?
（カカシ）とにかく
慎重に近づきましょう。
In any case,
let's approach cautiously.
（みんな）あっ　先生！
– Sensei!
みんな！
Everyone!
フフフフフ。
やめろ！
子供たちに手を出すな！
Stop!
Don't lay a hand on the children!
フッ。
揃った…。
I got them all!
揃ったぞ　７本　すべて。
I got all seven of them!
やった～　やったぞ！
I did it! I actually did it!
これで　力を取り戻せる。
Now my "power" will return!
アハハハハハハハ！
《どうすれば…》
How can I…?!
《チャクラを食らう？》
Consume…chakra?
力の制御には　７本の音を
組み合わせたパターンを利用して→
One takes control of
the "power" by activating it
規定の手順にのっとり
起動させる。
with a combination of
seven "sounds."
力の放出量は　パターンの変化により
増減させることができる。
By varying the sound patterns,
you can increase and
decrease the level of "power."
音を利用した入力は
手動操作による更新→
Inputting this sound can
be a manual operation…
もしくは　七つ時ごとに
自動で感知　更新される。
Or it will automatically renew
its power every 12 hours.
音の組み合わせが
パターンにない不当な場合は→
If a certain sound pattern does
not exist and is not recognized,
前回の更新内容が維持される。
the previous pattern
will be maintained.
これが正しければ…。
If this is correct…
ああ！
Mina!
あっ！　ミィナ！
う…。
How could you be so reckless?!
なんで　こんなムチャを！
Because…
We wanted…
だって…。
先生に…。
…to see you, Sensei!
（ファズ）先生に会いたいもん！
アハハハハハ！
Amazing…amazing…
This is amazing!
すげえ…　すげえ　すげえぞ！
This is impressive…
驚いたな。
これが　天の矛？
This is…the "Ama no Hoko"?
If this is the activation pattern,
これが起動のパターンなら
力の解放は…。
the way to release "power" is…!
（カカシ）
過ぎた野心は　身を滅ぼす。
Too much ambition…is destructive.
これは　もう
人の扱う代物じゃない。
This is no longer something
people should use.
昔の手配書リストも確認したよ。
I verified it on an old bulletin
of wanted persons…
暁と争って
死んだと思われていたようだな。
Apparently,
it was believed you died
in a scuffle with the Akatsuki.
口寄せ術を得意とし→
You specialized in
the Summoning Jutsu,
殺めた人の数は
数千ともいわれた　殺人狂。
and you were known
as a homicidal maniac
who claimed
several thousand victims.
禁術の穢土転生を
大蛇丸とともに研究していた。
Along with Orochimaru,
you researched the forbidden
Reanimation Jutsu…
フフッ。
観念しろ　ディソナス！
Give up, Disonasu!
お兄ちゃん！
シセル！
Brother!
Shiseru?
（飛段）テメエは！
You're…!
ソイツは　俺がやる。
That guy is mine!
ナルト君！
Naruto!
（サクラ）ナルト！
（ヒナタ）ナルト君！
Naruto…
ゴホゴホ！
（デイダラ）フフッ。
うん！
ハハハハ！
It's all over for you guys!
テメエら　これで終わりだ！
Ino! Choji!
いの！　チョウジ！
あっ！
Sakura!
（サイ）サクラ！
Get a little taste of some art!
芸術を味わえ！
Art is…
芸術は爆発だ！
an explosion!
《シカマル：ヤツが儀式を行うには
呪印を描かなきゃならねえ。
He needs to create a Curse Mark
in order to perform the ritual.
その隙を与えなきゃいいんだ》
So we can't give him
a chance to do so…
まさか…。
No way…
うわぁ～！
ぐっ…　ハァ　ハァ　ハァ。
なんだ　お前は…。
What are you…?
お前の　その力！
This power of yours…
俺は　今まで
いろんな大切なことを→
Over the years, I've been taught
a lot of important things
いろんな人に教わってきた。
今さっきだって
すげぇ　強い人に→
from a lot of people….
大切なことを教わったんだ。
Even now, I learned something
from an incredibly strong person.
俺の力は→
螺旋丸や仙術や
九尾のチャクラなんかじゃねえ！
My "power" isn't the Rasengan
or Sage Jutsu…
俺の力は…。
or the Nine Tails' chakra.
My power is…
ここだ！
right here!
サイ！
Sai!
A reanimated shinobi
that doesn't resurrect?
穢土転生の忍が復活しないだと？
（ガイ）どうやら
捨て駒にしたようだな。
I guess…
they were sacrificial pawns.
やっと捕らえたぜ！
We finally got you!
テメエ！
Why you—!
アンタの能力は
サポートがなけりゃ生かせねえ。
Your ability is useless without
back-up support.
It's because it requires
so many steps.
長ったらしい段取りのせいでな。
サポートか…　なら。
Support, huh? Well then…
ったく　世話の焼けるダンナだぜ！
Damn, he's such a nuisance!
これで…。
Now then!
（ヤマト）これ以上は　させないよ。
That's as far as you'll go.
こんな…　とこで！
諦めろ。
As if…
I'm gonna…
こんなとこで
諦めてたまるか！
Give it up.
Like I'm gonna give up
at this point!
あん！？
This is…!
これは！
Hey! What the hell…?
Damn you!
おい　何だよ　テメエ！
どうやら　お前の元になってる
クローン蛇ってのには→
Looks like that clone snake
that constitutes you
has a big defect…
大きな欠陥があるみてえだな。
急速に成長する分
寿命も短いってとこか。
They reach maturity quickly,
but their lifespan
is just as short.
That about explains it.
念のため　あと二十手ほどの対策を
考えていたが→
Just in case, I came up
with 20 more strategies…
必要なかったみてぇだな。
I guess that wasn't necessary.
（みんな）うわぁ～！
What was that just now?!
何？　今の…。
崩れ落ちている。
The ground caved in…
ここの地面は→
This terrain was raised up
and supported by tree ro
木の根に支えられて
浮いている状態なんだ。
早く　ホールから逃げないと。
え？　うん。
（ミィナ）先生　あれは止まらないの？
世界を覆いし　その力は
世界を滅ぼす。
力…。
あの力を浴びれば…。
ヘヘッ。
＜旬の魚が大好きな豆助＞
豆助　きょうのお魚は
今が旬のアレよ
＜　その魚とは…＞
＜　それは幼いころ→
群れるさまが
花に似ていることから→